All right so let's get started with some quanta fires.
好吧，让我们开始一些量子火灾。
I'm going to use count and non non for uncountable to mark these just so you know which ones they should
我将使用 count 和 non non 表示不可数来标记这些，以便您知道应该使用哪些
be connected to.
被连接到。
Which nouns they should be connected to.
它们应该连接到哪些名词。
So a little and little are these countable or uncountable.
所以这些是可数的或不可数的。
Actually none.
其实没有。
OK.
好的。
So these are both uncountable not none.
所以这些都是不可数的，不是没有的。
It's a different thing.
这是另一回事。
Non non uncountable.
非不可数。
So we wouldn't say for example a little cups we wouldn't say little cups although that does have a different
所以我们不会说例如小杯子，我们不会说小杯子，尽管它确实有不同
meaning.
意义。
If we're talking about little in this sense.
如果我们在这个意义上谈论很少。
But if we use little in this sense then it's not a quanta fire it's an adjective.
但如果我们在这个意义上使用很少，那么它就不是量子火，而是一个形容词。
OK so let's let's get started a little is positive and little is often negative.
好的，让我们开始吧，一点点是积极的，一点点通常是消极的。
That means when it's good news that we have a little of something right.
这意味着当我们有一些正确的事情是好消息时。
It's good news it's good not zero.
这是好消息，它不是零。
Then we use a little if it's bad news we should have many maybe or I guess I should say a lot of something
然后我们使用一点，如果这是坏消息，我们应该有很多，或者我想我应该说很多
and we don't we use little little.
我们不使用很少的东西。
So we usually focus on the negative for this one and the positive for this one for example let's do
所以我们通常关注这个的负面和这个的正面，例如让我们做
a couple examples of each.
每个的几个例子。
OK.
好的。
There's a there's a little coffee left if you want some.
如果你想要一些，还有一点咖啡。
It's not gone.
它没有消失。
That's great.
那太棒了。
That means I can have some good.
这意味着我可以有一些好处。
There's a little coffee left.
还剩一点咖啡。
It's a positive statement OK.
这是一个积极的声明。
I've got a little time.
我有一点时间。
What's up.
这是怎么回事。
Someone asks for your time.
有人问你的时间。
Hey do you think you could help me with something.
嘿，你认为你能帮我做点什么吗？
Yeah I've got a little time.
是的，我有一点时间。
What's up.
这是怎么回事。 什么意思，我怎么帮你。
So this is a positive statement means I have some time to give you now a lot is often used for things
所以这是一个积极的陈述意味着我现在有一些时间给你很多经常用于的事情
that are a little larger than we say and that's usually a good thing but we don't want to express it
比我们说的要大一点，这通常是一件好事，但我们不想表达
to confidently we want to be a little bit understated.
自信地我们想要低调一点。
This is quite common in British English in particular.
这在英式英语中尤其常见。
So for example let's say you post a video and you suddenly become a famous Internet celebrity and someone
例如，假设您发布了一个视频，然后您突然成为了著名的互联网名人和某人
asks you about how things are going for you right.
询问您事情进展如何。
You could say well it's it's a little little hectic right now a little hectic right now hectic means
你可以说它现在有点忙 现在有点忙 忙的意思
very busy so you're probably very busy or probably totally swamped.
很忙，所以你可能很忙，或者可能完全被淹没了。
And you're wanting to express it in an understated way so you use a little very common to use a little
而且你想用一种低调的方式来表达它所以你用一点很常见来用一点
and also a bit which we'll talk about in a bit.
还有一点我们稍后会谈到。
Very soon.
很快。
OK so I'm a little a little tired maybe I'm exhausted maybe I'm very tired and I want to go home but
好的，所以我有点累了，也许我累了，也许我很累，我想回家，但是
you don't say to the host of the party I'm exhausted.
你不要对派对的主人说我累了。
I want to go home.
我想回家。
You say I'm a little tired.
你说我有点累。
I think I'll go home.
我想我会回家的。
No I should probably go instead of saying I'm exhausted.
不，我可能应该去而不是说我筋疲力尽。
All right.
好的。
How about Little.
小小怎么样。
Well we focus more on the negative.
好吧，我们更多地关注负面因素。
The fact that we're almost close to zero and that's not a good thing.
事实上，我们几乎接近于零，这不是一件好事。
For example there's too little time to finish the project.
例如，完成项目的时间太少。
It's terrible.
它是可怕的。
That means we don't have enough it's not enough Not enough time.
这意味着我们没有足够的时间还不够。
This is bad.
这是不好的。
This is bad there's too little time.
可惜时间太少了。
We don't have enough time.
我们没有足够的时间。
We won't finish low.
我们不会完成低。
That's not good.
这不好。
That's not good at all.
这一点都不好。
We don't want that.
我们不希望那样。
OK.
好的。
Let's try another one.
让我们尝试另一个。
You have very little to do with the investigation.
你与调查无关。
You can go.
你可以走了。
OK.
好的。
So there's an investigation maybe someone's in trouble maybe you're a witness you saw something happen
所以有一个调查也许有人有麻烦也许你是目击者你看到了一些事情发生
and you're at the police station and they were asking you some questions but really you were far away
你在警察局，他们问你一些问题，但你真的很远
you weren't really involved.
你并没有真正参与。
Maybe this is something we'd see on a TV show.
也许这是我们会在电视节目中看到的东西。
You just saw something happening.
你刚刚看到有事情发生。
And finally it's late and they say well you had very little to do with the investigation which means
最后是晚了，他们说你和调查没什么关系，这意味着
almost nothing.
几乎没有。
And we're focusing on the fact that it's almost nothing.
我们专注于它几乎没有的事实。
OK you can go you can go.
好的，你可以去你可以去。
So we're getting closer and closer to zero.
所以我们越来越接近于零。
And that's not to say it's a bad thing.
这并不是说这是一件坏事。
But the emphasis is on the fact that it's close to zero as opposed to a little which is focusing on
但重点在于它接近于零，而不是专注于
the fact that it's not zero.
它不是零的事实。
I hope that makes sense.
我希望这是有道理的。
I hope that difference is clear.
我希望区别很明显。
OK.
好的。
There's so little food again.
又是这么少吃的。
We have almost no food.
我们几乎没有食物。
There's so little food.
食物这么少。
But if we say I have a little food that means probably you asked me for some.
但如果我们说我有一点食物，那意味着你可能向我要了一些。
And I'm willing to give you some.
我愿意给你一些。
Here you are.
给你。
So it's usually a little more positive.
所以通常会更积极一些。
Let's move on.
让我们继续。